<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recruiting on Simon says</title>
    <link>//simonmika.com/tags/recruiting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recruiting on Simon says</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 17:32:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//simonmika.com/tags/recruiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Programming Interview</title>
      <link>//simonmika.com/article/programming-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 17:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//simonmika.com/article/programming-interview/</guid>
      <description>When recruiting an artist like a designer or architect, you ask to see their portfolio. When you recruit a scientist you take a look at the papers they authored. Why? Because they are all professions where the individuals brilliance matters a lot for the results they produce. That is also the case with programmers.
So why do we not spend more time looking at a candidates past programming achievements? The answer is probably due to a combination of factors:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recruiting Process</title>
      <link>//simonmika.com/article/recruiting-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 23:18:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//simonmika.com/article/recruiting-process/</guid>
      <description>Good programmers are more like artists then sweatshop workers. If we are serious about recruiting good programmers we should not treat them like sweatshop workers.
An employment is somewhat like a marriage. The relationship starts by finding a partner on a dating/job listing site or thru the referral of a trusted friend. After that you start dating/interviewing. After a period of dating/interviewing you end up writing a marriage/employment contract.
One of the keys to a successful dating/interviewing is for it to be reciprocal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Star Programmers</title>
      <link>//simonmika.com/article/rock-star-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 23:18:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//simonmika.com/article/rock-star-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I come across programmers that view themselves as rock stars. Some even label themselves code ninjas. As if they are some kind of programming super hero with special powers.
While a do realize where this comes from. A good programmer can easily be more then ten times as productive as an average one. We do also need good raw models and front figures for our profession.
 Programming is not a one man show.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>